<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Interactive Fiction Reader</string>
    <string name="theString">Welcome!</string>
    <string name="intro">Frog Prince\n\nOnce upon a time, there was a  humble frog. You!\n\nYou live in a small pond next to the royal castle. You have heard rumor of princesses in said castle with the ability to turn humble frogs like you into a prince with a simple kiss.\n\nBut what princess would want to kiss a frog anyway? Probably just a tale to tell the little tadpoles.\n\nAs you sit on your lilypad, you notice a few flies buzzing around your head. You have not had lunch, but you remember spying a heron patrolling the skys a few minutes ago. It seems to have gone, but maybe you should check again before making any sudden movements.\n\nDo you:</string>
    <string name="checksky">You decide safe is better than sorry as your eyes scan the sky and trees for the heron. Your fears are realized when you spot it in the branches of a nearby pine. A Bluebottle fly buzzes and lands on a dry section of the lily pad you are on. Darn, those are your favorites you think to yourself but now\'s not the time for a snack.\n\nTwo options come to your mind. The heron doesn\'t seem to have noticed you but is fairly close. You could retreat into the water and find a good hiding spot. The heron would almost certainly notice, but you\'d have the benefit of a head start and the murky water below.\n\nYou also could sit and wait on the lily. The heron hasn\'t noticed you and won\'t as long as you stay still enough. You just have to suppress the urge to croak or eat any of the flies that are almost flaunting their proximity to you.</string>
    <string name="pondretreat">Not today heron! You plop yourself ever so gracefully into the water below. You have just the spot picked out for such an occasion; a muddy little outlet where there are some long grasses perfect for hiding.\n\nYou cozy up to some grass, your head popped just above the waterline. You snap your third eyelid open that you use for swimming so you can see whether anything in the sky is after you.\n\nThe heron is indeed in mid flight swooping down near where you were perched just a moment before. You see the bird rise from the water with a frog in its mouth.\n\nOh Delores. She did tend to favor a spot on the shore near your favorite lily. You are saddened by her loss but obviously made the right choice; if you had stayed there you would have befallen the same fate.\n\nRest in peace Delores.</string>
    <string name="staystill">You breathe slow and deliberately and repress the urge to fill your vocal sack with air. It is not the time for movement or noise. Zen vibes time. You act the part of a frog statue. You are one with the lily. The lily is you. Your mind begins to drift to the meaning of life and what things may be like outside of the pond.\n\nYou take a look back to the branch with the heron, but the heron is gone! This is great and means lunch time is just a quick sky-scan away!\n\nSPLASH! You turn and look behind you. The heron is mere meters away! Not good. You prime your legs to launch yourself into the water but hesitate. What is that in the Heron\'s beak?\n\nDelores. She used to sit on the edge of the pond and eat flies right by your favorite lily. That\'s what - or who is in the heron\'s mouth. You watch in horror as the heron takes off in flight. You feel a tinge of regret for being annoyed with Delores for eating all the good flies this season. In a very tragic way this means you are safe for the moment.</string>
    <string name="poordelores">C\'est la vie you\'re afraid - these things happen. There\'s nothing to do about it but be more careful next time.\n\nNow then what was it you were doing before your life was on the line?</string>
    <string name="flyeat2">Your tongue darts out lightning-fast and ensnares the closest fly. Mmm Bluebottle fly. These are one of your favorite treats and only come out during a few weeks in the summertime.\n\nYou feel the sun warming your body while you perch on the lily pad while you eye another Bluebottle to gobble up. This really is the life, isn\'t it?\n\n\"Oh my goodness! That poor little frog getting snatched up by the heron!\" You hear behind you. You turn to look at the source of the voice.</string>
    <string name="lookcastle2">There must be more to life than sitting eating flies and escaping predators you think. The tale of the princess and the frog comes to your mind. You instinctually look up toward the castle. You let out an unintentional croak at what you see standing at the edge of the pond.</string>
    <string name="seeprincess">The castle princess. The literal princess of the castle stands before you clothed in a summery flower dress.\n\n\"Oh my,\" she says, \"This really is no place for a frog to be spending their time. Not with these water fowl around ready to gobble you up.\" She crouches toward you.\n\nThe princess starts to reach toward you. Oh my \"she can\'t ruin that fine dress of hers trying to reach across the pond\" you think. Better hop to her.\n\nHow bizarre is this? Never in your wildest dreams would the princess of the castle take any notice of you. and now here you are, hopping into her open arms!\n\nWith one final expertly-executed jump, you land directly in the hands of the princess.</string>
    <string name="frogbreathend">You poor thing! You must have been so scared to have jumped into a stranger\'s arms like this. Was that your friend that heron took away in its beak?\n\n\"Not particularly,\" you think to yourself, but you are exceptionally grateful for being saved from the dangers of the pond.\n\nThe princess holds you up close to her face. What is this feeling? Excitement? Do you really believe in that princess-frog-magic stuff? You look into the face of the princess. You do believe. You have to. There has to be something else. There is something else! And you\'re going to see it! You\'re going to be a prince. She must know this too. Why else would she be holding you so close to her face if not to kiss you? You purse your frog-lips and slowly close your eyes.\n\n\"Oh what is that smell?\" The princess says. \"Your breath absolutely reeks of flies little frog friend! I suppose Mama would be terribly cross with me for bringing a pond critter into the castle. I\'m afraid you\'ll have to stay here.\"\n\nShe sets you down in the gentlest way possible. \"You do seem to know how to get along in this pond! I suppose I worry too much. Bye Bye little frog!\"\n\nAnd with that the princess turns and begins heading toward the castle. \"Wow a real-life princess!\" You think to yourself. \"A prince I may not be but what a story to tell being held by the princess herself.\"\n\nYou are good at this frog-life you think. Enjoying the sun and the water. Eating those wonderful, juicy, summer flies. What more could a frog want?\n\nThe end.</string>
    <string name="princeend">You poor thing! You must have been so scared to have jumped into a stranger\'s arms like this. Was that your friend that heron took away in its beak?\n\n\"Not particularly,\" you think to yourself, but you are exceptionally grateful for being saved from the dangers of the pond.\n\nThe princess holds you up close to her face. What is this feeling? Excitement? Do you really believe in that princess-frog-magic stuff? You look into the face of the princess. You do believe. You have to. There has to be something else. There is something else! And you\'re going to see it! You\'re going to be a prince. She must know this too. Why else would she be holding you so close to her face if not to kiss you? You purse your frog-lips and slowly close your eyes.\n\n\"Is it a kiss you want?\" The princess laughs. Her voice ringing out beautifully like the summer breeze. She gives you a quick peck and sets you down.\n\nMagic engulfs your body and your entire being begins to change. Legs, arms head. A green suit unfolds as you change and grow. You now stand even taller than the princess herself! Your neck stretches and narrows. The sensation feels strange on your vocal chords and you instinctually try to croak. Except you don\'t. You let out a kind of sigh. The princess stands in complete shock in front of you.\n\n\"This is it! My chance to experience life outside the pond! How absolutely incredible,\" you think to yourself.\n\nYou do a bow and bend your arm below your chest. \"My lady,\" you say.\n\nOh how very regal this new you is.\n\nThe end.</string>
    <string name="muddyfrogend">You land with a splat. Murky pond water soiling the princess\' beautiful dress. \"Oh no! Ma will be ever so cross with me for ruining my summer dress.\"\n\nShe sets you down in the gentlest way possible. \"You do seem to know how to get along in this pond! I suppose I worry too much. Bye Bye little frog!\"\n\nAnd with that the princess turns and begins heading toward the castle. \"Wow a real-life princess!\" You think to yourself. \"A prince I may not be but what a story to tell being held by the princess herself.\"\n\nYou are good at this frog-life you think. Enjoying the sun and the water. Eating those wonderful, juicy, summer flies. The ways of humans and royalty don\'t really suit you anyway. A beautiful pond right next to the royal castle. What more could a frog want?\n\nThe end.</string>
    <string name="dieheron">Alas, you have died.</string>
    <string name="lookcastle1">Your head always has been in the clouds. What a dream living as a human in the castle would be. You turn to look at the castle and see a beautiful girl standing in a summery flower dress standing at the edge of the pond. The princess!\n\nYou let out a huge croak in disbelief. The princess hears you and turns to look at you; the summer sun shining through her auburn hair making her look completely radiant.\n\nThis is an absolute dream. You hear the beating of wings. \"She must be an angel as well,\" you think, \"a beautiful angel princess.\"\n\nSuddenly the entire pond falls right out from under you. You feel pain in your back and belly. The pond and bluebottle flies become smaller and smaller as you dare to move your eyeline up... or is it down? You think you are upside down.\n\nYour eyes meet what you feared. The flapping wings of the Heron. Your body entraped between its long beak. Your pond home disappears behind trees and you can make out just the top of the castle spires. </string>
    <string name="flyeat1">Your tongue darts out lightning-fast and ensnares the closest fly. Mmm Bluebottle fly. These are one of your favorite treats and only come out during a few weeks in the summertime.\n\nYou feel the sun warming your body while you perch on the lily pad while you eye another Bluebottle to gobble up. This really is the life, isn\'t it?\n\nYou prepare your tongue for another strike when suddenly the entire pond falls right out from under you. You feel pain in your back and belly. The pond and bluebottle flies become smaller and smaller as you dare to move your eyeline up... or is it down? You think you are upside down.\n\nYour eyes meet what you feared. The flapping wings of the Heron. Your body entraped between its long beak. Your pond home disappears behind trees and you can make out just the top of the castle spires. </string>
</resources>